<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jefferson Heard</title>
    <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/tags/recipes/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jefferson Heard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://jeffersonheard.github.io/tags/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Night Dinners: Lemongrass Curry Soup</title>
      <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/12/saturday-night-dinners-lemongrass-curry-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/12/saturday-night-dinners-lemongrass-curry-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was going for something Thai-ish without following any particular recipe. What
I came out with was pretty incredible. A lot like Tom Kha, but not exactly.  Use
a fairly light vegetable broth for this recipe: either a miso broth or I use the
Swanson&amp;rsquo;s organic vegetable broth.  The taste of this one is at once hearty and
very very full of Spring. The whole thing took about 35 minutes from start to
finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tbl massaman curry paste or 1/2tbl red curry paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tbl olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 cloves garlic, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 onion, sliced and halved (to make &amp;ldquo;noodles&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; lb fresh baby spinach, trimmed and washed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cucumber, diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cp cashew halves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 cp vegetable broth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 can coconut milk, full fat (Thai Kitchen is my favorite)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp shredded kaffir lime leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tbl lemongrass paste (comes in a tube at the grocery store)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cp chopped mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cp cubed chicken or Quorn tenders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-4 tbl lime juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heat the oil on medium in a heavy stockpot.  Add the curry paste and fry until
fragrant and the oil changes color.  Add the onions and garlic and cashews and
chicken and satuee until the onions have begun to wilt and everything is coated
nicely. Add broth, mushrooms, lemongrass paste, kaffir lime leaf, lime juice,
and simmer for 12 minutes.  Add the spinach and rice noodles, and bring to a
boil for 6 minutes.  Remove from heat, sitr in the coconut milk, add cucumber,
and serve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Brunch: Fried Pears and Pecans</title>
      <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/12/sunday-brunch-fried-pears-and-pecans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/12/sunday-brunch-fried-pears-and-pecans/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I should really start taking pictures if I&amp;rsquo;m going to post recipes. But imagine
if you will a plate of pear slices, fried until they are golden brown on both
sides, the outside crispy, the inside smooth and sweet, and all of it covered in
streusel that tastes amazing. Got it? Good. Here goes.  &lt;strong&gt;Serves 1.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tbl butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small handful of fresh sage leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cp crushed pecans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1tbl Brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slice my pear flat, with slices about &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; inch thick (half a cm). Heat a cast
iron skillet on medium until it&amp;rsquo;s thoroughly warm. Add the butter and salt and
brown it. It will start to smell &amp;ldquo;nutty&amp;rdquo; and the foam will have mostly settled
when it&amp;rsquo;s ready. When the butter is brown, add the sage leaves and let them fry
for a second or three. Then add the pears and arrange in the pan so that they
are flat. Let them fry until the surface is golden, about 8 minutes on a side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove the pears with a slotted spoon when they&amp;rsquo;re done enough for you, and put
on a plate.  Then quickly toss the pecans in the pan, sprinkle with brown sugar,
cinnamon, and nutmeg, and stir around to toast gently till the mixture binds a
bit and soaks up the butter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spread this mixture over the pears and serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in any way, shape, or form a balanced breakfast; but it sure does
go amazingly well with coffee or Earl Grey tea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Night Dinner: Three-Alarm Plate of Awesome</title>
      <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/11/saturday-night-dinner-three-alarm-plate-of-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/11/saturday-night-dinner-three-alarm-plate-of-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is a three-alarm plate of awesome? Roasted red peppers and roasted
eggplant, tossed and fried in mustard oil, bay leaf, and spices (cayenne,
cinnamon, turmeric).  Served over polenta, and it was &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe, and sorry, this one&amp;rsquo;s a bit involved, because roasting peppers requires
attention:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 red bell peppers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 jalapeños&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 med. eggplant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;olive oil for brushing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2tsp cayenne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2tsp turmeric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1tbl mustard seed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bay leaf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 shallot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat the oven to 500 degrees, Coat the skin of the peppers in olive oil
(lightly) and set down on a cookie sheet (you can use the bare oven, but be
prepared for a mess if the pepper sags through).  Roast on each side of the
pepper 8-10 minutes, turning when the pepper is thoroughly blistered.  Take out
the peppers and then cover them for 30 minutes so that they steam themselves. A
bowl over a plate will do just fine.  The point is that if they steam
themselves, they&amp;rsquo;re that much easier to peel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, while all this is going on, slice the eggplant in half lengthwise, then cut
a crosshatch into each half.  Sprinkle with kosher salt and set aside for 30 min
while the pepper is roasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the pepper is done roasting, squeeze the eggplant face down, gently, over
the sink so that the salty juice comes out, brush the salt off, and then coat
the surface with oil (lightly, once again).  Drop the oven down to 400, put the
eggplant face down on some foil or cookie sheets, and roast those for another
half hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you time this right, the pepper will be ready to peel by the time the
eggplant&amp;rsquo;s ready to come out of the oven, and you&amp;rsquo;ll feel like you know kung-fu
for all your sheer perfect timing.  If you&amp;rsquo;re me, you peel the pepper and set it
aside for 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take everything that&amp;rsquo;s roasted and chop it up.  Heat a tablespoon and a half of
olive oil in a pan until it shimmers.  Add the bay leaf, chopped shallot, and
mustard seeds and fry till the seeds begin to pop.  add the turmeric and fry for
no more than 10 seconds. Toss in the chopped peppers and eggplant and add
cayenne to taste.  Stir-fry for 5 minutes, remove from heat, and serve.  My
chosen side was polenta, but basmati rice would work just as well.  As for pics,
I&amp;rsquo;d post a pic, but I ate it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>