<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jefferson Heard</title>
    <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/tags/spicy/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jefferson Heard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://jeffersonheard.github.io/tags/spicy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Night Dinner: Three-Alarm Plate of Awesome</title>
      <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/11/saturday-night-dinner-three-alarm-plate-of-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/11/saturday-night-dinner-three-alarm-plate-of-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is a three-alarm plate of awesome? Roasted red peppers and roasted
eggplant, tossed and fried in mustard oil, bay leaf, and spices (cayenne,
cinnamon, turmeric).  Served over polenta, and it was &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe, and sorry, this one&amp;rsquo;s a bit involved, because roasting peppers requires
attention:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 red bell peppers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 jalapeños&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 med. eggplant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;olive oil for brushing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2tsp cayenne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2tsp turmeric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1tbl mustard seed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bay leaf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 shallot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat the oven to 500 degrees, Coat the skin of the peppers in olive oil
(lightly) and set down on a cookie sheet (you can use the bare oven, but be
prepared for a mess if the pepper sags through).  Roast on each side of the
pepper 8-10 minutes, turning when the pepper is thoroughly blistered.  Take out
the peppers and then cover them for 30 minutes so that they steam themselves. A
bowl over a plate will do just fine.  The point is that if they steam
themselves, they&amp;rsquo;re that much easier to peel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, while all this is going on, slice the eggplant in half lengthwise, then cut
a crosshatch into each half.  Sprinkle with kosher salt and set aside for 30 min
while the pepper is roasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the pepper is done roasting, squeeze the eggplant face down, gently, over
the sink so that the salty juice comes out, brush the salt off, and then coat
the surface with oil (lightly, once again).  Drop the oven down to 400, put the
eggplant face down on some foil or cookie sheets, and roast those for another
half hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you time this right, the pepper will be ready to peel by the time the
eggplant&amp;rsquo;s ready to come out of the oven, and you&amp;rsquo;ll feel like you know kung-fu
for all your sheer perfect timing.  If you&amp;rsquo;re me, you peel the pepper and set it
aside for 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take everything that&amp;rsquo;s roasted and chop it up.  Heat a tablespoon and a half of
olive oil in a pan until it shimmers.  Add the bay leaf, chopped shallot, and
mustard seeds and fry till the seeds begin to pop.  add the turmeric and fry for
no more than 10 seconds. Toss in the chopped peppers and eggplant and add
cayenne to taste.  Stir-fry for 5 minutes, remove from heat, and serve.  My
chosen side was polenta, but basmati rice would work just as well.  As for pics,
I&amp;rsquo;d post a pic, but I ate it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>