<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jefferson Heard</title>
    <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/tags/reviews/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jefferson Heard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://jeffersonheard.github.io/tags/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Secret of Kells and Song of the Sea</title>
      <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/11/review-secret-of-kells-and-song-of-the-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/11/review-secret-of-kells-and-song-of-the-sea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://static.rogerebert.com/uploads/review/primary_image/reviews/the-secret-of-kells-2010/hero_EB20100331REVIEWS100339983AR.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-secret-of-kells-2010&#34;&gt;Roger Ebert&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pangur Bán&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Pangur, white Pangur, How happy we are &lt;br /&gt;
Alone together, scholar and cat &lt;br /&gt;
Each has his own work to do daily; &lt;br /&gt;
For you it is hunting, for me study. &lt;br /&gt;
Your shining eye watches the wall; &lt;br /&gt;
My feeble eye is fixed on a book. &lt;br /&gt;
You rejoice, when your claws entrap a mouse; &lt;br /&gt;
I rejoice when my mind fathoms a problem. &lt;br /&gt;
Pleased with his own art, neither hinders the other; &lt;br /&gt;
Thus we live ever without tedium and envy. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anonymous (translation from the Irish by W.H. Auden)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When animated movies win or are nominated for Oscars, it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be an indication
that they deserve a place in our collective consciousness. However, when those
movies are foreign, or they don&amp;rsquo;t follow contemporary animation trends, they
still risk falling into obscurity undeservedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two of my favorite animated films of all time are &lt;strong&gt;Secret of Kells&lt;/strong&gt; and
&lt;strong&gt;Song of the Sea&lt;/strong&gt;. They are both animated by the same Irish animation studio,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cartoon_Saloon&#34;&gt;Cartoon Saloon&lt;/a&gt;, and both use a
style of animation that adheres closely to the style of art embodied in
illuminated manuscripts such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Book_of_Kells&#34;&gt;Book of Kells&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The animation is luminous. Saturated colors, flat cel style animation, and
intricate, calligraphic lines make the story feel like you&amp;rsquo;re being read to
even while watching the movie. They recall an earlier movie, not as well done,
but still equally beautiful: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Thief_and_the_Cobbler&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Thief and the Cobbler&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
whose animation loosely follows early Islamic art styles (an effect which is a bit
broken by animating human characters in the movie, since most Islamic art is
iconoclastic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poem above is interwoven with its Irish language source throughout Secret of
Kells in a modal song that further serves to make the story feel like a fairy tale
from a lost age, discovered again by the viewers. The &amp;ldquo;sidekick&amp;rdquo; is a fairy who
appears to the main character first as a girl, then as a cat, Pangur Ban, who
serves both as the hero&amp;rsquo;s helper and the key to the saga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Song of the Sea, Irish music and the myth of the &lt;em&gt;selkie&lt;/em&gt; serves to transport
the viewer along with the animation. The story itself recalls The Little Mermaid
(or its most recent animated retelling, Miyazaki&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://movies.disney.com/ponyo&#34;&gt;Ponyo&lt;/a&gt;.
The main character is a little girl, Saoirse (appropriately, a Galeicization of Circe)
who only knows that she has no mother, and that her father wants her to stay
away from the sea. She herself is half-Selkie, and her adventures lead her
closer and closer to the mythic world she came from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secret of Kells tells a mythologized story of the preservation of Western culture
after the fall of Rome by the Irish monks who penned the Book of Kells. Central
to the story is a magic stone that allows the monks to see the page to do their
finest and most intricate illumination work. The villains, the Viking Horde, are
thoroughly menacing. Their animation and their presence remind me a lot of
Samurai Jack&amp;rsquo;s demon adversary, &lt;em&gt;Aku&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Song of the Sea was nominated for an Oscar in 2015, but lost out to &lt;strong&gt;Frozen&lt;/strong&gt;.
Secret of Kells lost to &lt;strong&gt;Up&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to win an Oscar on a year with a
strong showing by Disney, but neither of these films deserve to be relegate to
second-tier viewing. To those who know these movies, they will become treasured
classics, on the same shelf as Sprited Away or Kiki&amp;rsquo;s Delivery Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As foreign as the films may be to American viewers who only know them from their
Oscar nominations, all the elements you expect in an animated movie are there.
Action, adventure, whimsical sidekicks, villains.  And yet, they never feel like
they are trying to be Disney, like much non-Disney American animation. It more
feels like a nod to the giants of animation than an attempt to win audience by
copying them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secret of Kells and Song of the Sea are both often available on Amazon and
Netflix streaming sites. I highly recommend them to anyone who loves a
good fairy tale on a rainy day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>