<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jefferson Heard</title>
    <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/categories/personal/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jefferson Heard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://jeffersonheard.github.io/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipes: Chicken (or Turkey) Soup for the Soul and Everything Else</title>
      <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2017/01/recipes-chicken-or-turkey-soup-for-the-soul-and-everything-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2017/01/recipes-chicken-or-turkey-soup-for-the-soul-and-everything-else/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been sick for most of a month. This almost never happens to me. One cold followed by bronchitis, followed by another cold, followed by more bronchitis, but I&amp;rsquo;m finally on the mend. Towards the end of being sick I get bored and antsy before I&amp;rsquo;m well enough to go out, and that&amp;rsquo;s when I make this soup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have perfected my chicken soup over more than a decade of experimentation. Chicken soup is rich, perfectly seasoned broth, just enough fat, tender vegetables, a good proportion of chicken, and (if you like) noodles enough to make it into most bites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who don&amp;rsquo;t cook may not really understand where the &amp;ldquo;richness&amp;rdquo; of a fine broth comes from, nor what &amp;ldquo;bone broth&amp;rdquo; really means. Gelatin, collagen, cholesterols (&lt;a href=&#34;http://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2015/03/02/us-guidelines-dietary-cholesterol-limits.aspx&#34;&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of of dietary cholesterols anymore, say the AMA!&lt;/a&gt;), and esters released from boiling down the carcass - everything that&amp;rsquo;s not meat - make a smooth broth with depth that is unparalleled in its ability to warm and restore a person from the inside out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my recipe is really about getting the broth perfect and seasoning it well. You can use any vegetables. They don&amp;rsquo;t have to be the freshest in your fridge, even. I would avoid bitter greens in my soup. If you want greens, use kale or baby spinach, as they will not have such a tendency to leach tannins. For a base broth, I use Swanson&amp;rsquo;s Organic Chicken Broth, but you could use any chicken broth that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have added sugar or MSG (not that there&amp;rsquo;s anything wrong with MSG, but there&amp;rsquo;s no need for it since we&amp;rsquo;re bulking the broth up ourselves).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re in the USA, get an organic chicken; they taste better. In fact, get a free range chicken if you can find it. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if the flavor&amp;rsquo;s really any better between free range and not; but personally I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to treat the creatures we eat for food with respect and humanity. Regardless of how amusing the first episode of Porlandia is, the truth is that chickens and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X9wHzt6gBgI&#34;&gt;chicken farmers&lt;/a&gt; are often treated &lt;em&gt;terribly&lt;/em&gt; by the industry, and going to the extra trouble of finding a farmers market, locally raised, or otherwise ethically produced chicken really is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is important: start with a whole chicken / turkey&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes, you need the dark meat. But even more importantly, most of the stuff I mentioned earlier that makes the broth rich is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in the parts you get when you buy a &amp;ldquo;whole turkey breast&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;whole chicken breast.&amp;rdquo; Legs, thighs, wings, back; these are essential to the finished product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This soup freezes wonderfully, but don&amp;rsquo;t add noodles if you intend to freeze it. Depending on the size of your chicken, you may notice that the soup turns to jello in your fridge. This is a sign of a fantastic broth. Turkey broth will almost always do this, I find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, this one is involved. There&amp;rsquo;s not much prep-time, but there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of waiting. It&amp;rsquo;s worth every minute you put into it - trust me. This makes 12-18 servings, depending on whether you&amp;rsquo;re using chicken or turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;meat&#34;&gt;Meat&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 whole chicken, raw (&lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34;&gt;skin removed and set aside&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;liquids&#34;&gt;Liquids&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 cups canned or boxed chicken broth (I use Swanson&amp;rsquo;s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup white wine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;aromatics&#34;&gt;Aromatics&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 bay leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 stalk lemongrass, outer leaves peeled away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;vegetables&#34;&gt;Vegetables&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 oz fresh mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2-3 chopped carrots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-4 chopped stalks of celery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 chopped white onion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2-4 minced cloves of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;spices&#34;&gt;Spices&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2tsp cayenne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1tbl garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1tbl onion powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2tsp cumin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-2tsp coriander&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1tsp dried thyme or 4-5 sprigs fresh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1tsp white pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-1-cook-the-chicken-40-minutes&#34;&gt;Step 1. Cook the chicken. 40 minutes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are using a chicken&lt;/strong&gt; Skin the chicken. &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34;&gt;See the note&lt;/a&gt; about rendering chicken fat and using it in something. Pour the broth into a large stockpot and lower the chicken in. Add water to cover and bring to a boil, then lower the heat and simmer for 30-40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove the chicken from the broth and set it in a large bowl. Separate the meat from the bones as best you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are using a turkey.&lt;/strong&gt; Roast the turkey your favorite way (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rachaelrayshow.com/food/recipes/19178_cider_soaked_spatchcock_turkey/&#34;&gt;This is mine&lt;/a&gt;). Take the meat off the bones, pour off some of the roasting juices into the broth, and skip to step 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-2-enrich-the-broth-60-minutes&#34;&gt;Step 2. Enrich the broth. 60 minutes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smash the lemongrass stalk with a rolling pin. If it helps, think about all that aggression you&amp;rsquo;ve been suppressing. Now cut it into 3-4 even pieces. Add the bay leaf, lemongrass, and turkey or chicken carcass to the broth and bring to a boil. Cover and leave on a low boil (high simmer) for an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-3-make-the-soup-60-minutes-2-hours&#34;&gt;Step 3. Make the soup. 60 minutes - 2 hours&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove the carcass from the broth. You may need to strain the broth through a strainer to get everything out. If you used a turkey, add 2-3 cups of water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the vegetables and bring back to a boil. Lower the heat to a simmer, add the spices and the wine, and simmer for 1-2 hours. The longer and lower the simmer, the more the flavors will meld.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the vegetables are done, add the noodles and bring to a boil. Lower the heat to a simmer and add the chicken in. Simmer until the noodles are tender. Serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rendering and using chicken fat.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m a &amp;ldquo;waste not&amp;rdquo; kind of a person, doubly so when dealing with meat, because an animal died for my meal, and I consider careful preparation and the use of everything part of paying respect to that. Rendering chicken fat is easy and only takes an extra skillet while everything else is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, after rendering you end up with tasty fried chicken skins, which are like pork rinds or chicarones. Simply take them out of the fat then dust with salt, pepper, and cayenne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can sautee the vegetables for the soup in a tablespoon of the fat, or you can save it for anything savory you would use butter for frying or sauteeing. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great fat for stirfry myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raise a preferably cast-iron skillet to medium heat, add the skins, spread them out on the skillet, and cover with a mesh frying guard to keep your stove from looking like a fuzzy black and white photograph of a Jackson Pollack painting. Fry until they stop sounding like they&amp;rsquo;re frying or are starting to turn golden, and then turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove the skins, let the fat cool slightly, then pour the it off into a glass jar.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Brunch: Fried Pears and Pecans</title>
      <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/12/sunday-brunch-fried-pears-and-pecans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/12/sunday-brunch-fried-pears-and-pecans/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I should really start taking pictures if I&amp;rsquo;m going to post recipes. But imagine
if you will a plate of pear slices, fried until they are golden brown on both
sides, the outside crispy, the inside smooth and sweet, and all of it covered in
streusel that tastes amazing. Got it? Good. Here goes.  &lt;strong&gt;Serves 1.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tbl butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small handful of fresh sage leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cp crushed pecans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1tbl Brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slice my pear flat, with slices about &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; inch thick (half a cm). Heat a cast
iron skillet on medium until it&amp;rsquo;s thoroughly warm. Add the butter and salt and
brown it. It will start to smell &amp;ldquo;nutty&amp;rdquo; and the foam will have mostly settled
when it&amp;rsquo;s ready. When the butter is brown, add the sage leaves and let them fry
for a second or three. Then add the pears and arrange in the pan so that they
are flat. Let them fry until the surface is golden, about 8 minutes on a side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove the pears with a slotted spoon when they&amp;rsquo;re done enough for you, and put
on a plate.  Then quickly toss the pecans in the pan, sprinkle with brown sugar,
cinnamon, and nutmeg, and stir around to toast gently till the mixture binds a
bit and soaks up the butter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spread this mixture over the pears and serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in any way, shape, or form a balanced breakfast; but it sure does
go amazingly well with coffee or Earl Grey tea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Night Dinners: Lemongrass Curry Soup</title>
      <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/12/saturday-night-dinners-lemongrass-curry-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/12/saturday-night-dinners-lemongrass-curry-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was going for something Thai-ish without following any particular recipe. What
I came out with was pretty incredible. A lot like Tom Kha, but not exactly.  Use
a fairly light vegetable broth for this recipe: either a miso broth or I use the
Swanson&amp;rsquo;s organic vegetable broth.  The taste of this one is at once hearty and
very very full of Spring. The whole thing took about 35 minutes from start to
finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tbl massaman curry paste or 1/2tbl red curry paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tbl olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 cloves garlic, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 onion, sliced and halved (to make &amp;ldquo;noodles&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; lb fresh baby spinach, trimmed and washed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cucumber, diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cp cashew halves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 cp vegetable broth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 can coconut milk, full fat (Thai Kitchen is my favorite)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp shredded kaffir lime leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tbl lemongrass paste (comes in a tube at the grocery store)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cp chopped mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cp cubed chicken or Quorn tenders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-4 tbl lime juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heat the oil on medium in a heavy stockpot.  Add the curry paste and fry until
fragrant and the oil changes color.  Add the onions and garlic and cashews and
chicken and satuee until the onions have begun to wilt and everything is coated
nicely. Add broth, mushrooms, lemongrass paste, kaffir lime leaf, lime juice,
and simmer for 12 minutes.  Add the spinach and rice noodles, and bring to a
boil for 6 minutes.  Remove from heat, sitr in the coconut milk, add cucumber,
and serve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday Night Dinner: Three-Alarm Plate of Awesome</title>
      <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/11/saturday-night-dinner-three-alarm-plate-of-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/11/saturday-night-dinner-three-alarm-plate-of-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is a three-alarm plate of awesome? Roasted red peppers and roasted
eggplant, tossed and fried in mustard oil, bay leaf, and spices (cayenne,
cinnamon, turmeric).  Served over polenta, and it was &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe, and sorry, this one&amp;rsquo;s a bit involved, because roasting peppers requires
attention:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 red bell peppers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 jalapeños&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 med. eggplant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;olive oil for brushing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2tsp cayenne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2tsp turmeric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1tbl mustard seed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bay leaf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 shallot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat the oven to 500 degrees, Coat the skin of the peppers in olive oil
(lightly) and set down on a cookie sheet (you can use the bare oven, but be
prepared for a mess if the pepper sags through).  Roast on each side of the
pepper 8-10 minutes, turning when the pepper is thoroughly blistered.  Take out
the peppers and then cover them for 30 minutes so that they steam themselves. A
bowl over a plate will do just fine.  The point is that if they steam
themselves, they&amp;rsquo;re that much easier to peel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, while all this is going on, slice the eggplant in half lengthwise, then cut
a crosshatch into each half.  Sprinkle with kosher salt and set aside for 30 min
while the pepper is roasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the pepper is done roasting, squeeze the eggplant face down, gently, over
the sink so that the salty juice comes out, brush the salt off, and then coat
the surface with oil (lightly, once again).  Drop the oven down to 400, put the
eggplant face down on some foil or cookie sheets, and roast those for another
half hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you time this right, the pepper will be ready to peel by the time the
eggplant&amp;rsquo;s ready to come out of the oven, and you&amp;rsquo;ll feel like you know kung-fu
for all your sheer perfect timing.  If you&amp;rsquo;re me, you peel the pepper and set it
aside for 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take everything that&amp;rsquo;s roasted and chop it up.  Heat a tablespoon and a half of
olive oil in a pan until it shimmers.  Add the bay leaf, chopped shallot, and
mustard seeds and fry till the seeds begin to pop.  add the turmeric and fry for
no more than 10 seconds. Toss in the chopped peppers and eggplant and add
cayenne to taste.  Stir-fry for 5 minutes, remove from heat, and serve.  My
chosen side was polenta, but basmati rice would work just as well.  As for pics,
I&amp;rsquo;d post a pic, but I ate it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Secret of Kells and Song of the Sea</title>
      <link>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/11/review-secret-of-kells-and-song-of-the-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffersonheard.github.io/2016/11/review-secret-of-kells-and-song-of-the-sea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://static.rogerebert.com/uploads/review/primary_image/reviews/the-secret-of-kells-2010/hero_EB20100331REVIEWS100339983AR.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/the-secret-of-kells-2010&#34;&gt;Roger Ebert&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pangur Bán&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Pangur, white Pangur, How happy we are &lt;br /&gt;
Alone together, scholar and cat &lt;br /&gt;
Each has his own work to do daily; &lt;br /&gt;
For you it is hunting, for me study. &lt;br /&gt;
Your shining eye watches the wall; &lt;br /&gt;
My feeble eye is fixed on a book. &lt;br /&gt;
You rejoice, when your claws entrap a mouse; &lt;br /&gt;
I rejoice when my mind fathoms a problem. &lt;br /&gt;
Pleased with his own art, neither hinders the other; &lt;br /&gt;
Thus we live ever without tedium and envy. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anonymous (translation from the Irish by W.H. Auden)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When animated movies win or are nominated for Oscars, it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be an indication
that they deserve a place in our collective consciousness. However, when those
movies are foreign, or they don&amp;rsquo;t follow contemporary animation trends, they
still risk falling into obscurity undeservedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two of my favorite animated films of all time are &lt;strong&gt;Secret of Kells&lt;/strong&gt; and
&lt;strong&gt;Song of the Sea&lt;/strong&gt;. They are both animated by the same Irish animation studio,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cartoon_Saloon&#34;&gt;Cartoon Saloon&lt;/a&gt;, and both use a
style of animation that adheres closely to the style of art embodied in
illuminated manuscripts such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Book_of_Kells&#34;&gt;Book of Kells&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The animation is luminous. Saturated colors, flat cel style animation, and
intricate, calligraphic lines make the story feel like you&amp;rsquo;re being read to
even while watching the movie. They recall an earlier movie, not as well done,
but still equally beautiful: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Thief_and_the_Cobbler&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Thief and the Cobbler&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
whose animation loosely follows early Islamic art styles (an effect which is a bit
broken by animating human characters in the movie, since most Islamic art is
iconoclastic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poem above is interwoven with its Irish language source throughout Secret of
Kells in a modal song that further serves to make the story feel like a fairy tale
from a lost age, discovered again by the viewers. The &amp;ldquo;sidekick&amp;rdquo; is a fairy who
appears to the main character first as a girl, then as a cat, Pangur Ban, who
serves both as the hero&amp;rsquo;s helper and the key to the saga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Song of the Sea, Irish music and the myth of the &lt;em&gt;selkie&lt;/em&gt; serves to transport
the viewer along with the animation. The story itself recalls The Little Mermaid
(or its most recent animated retelling, Miyazaki&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://movies.disney.com/ponyo&#34;&gt;Ponyo&lt;/a&gt;.
The main character is a little girl, Saoirse (appropriately, a Galeicization of Circe)
who only knows that she has no mother, and that her father wants her to stay
away from the sea. She herself is half-Selkie, and her adventures lead her
closer and closer to the mythic world she came from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secret of Kells tells a mythologized story of the preservation of Western culture
after the fall of Rome by the Irish monks who penned the Book of Kells. Central
to the story is a magic stone that allows the monks to see the page to do their
finest and most intricate illumination work. The villains, the Viking Horde, are
thoroughly menacing. Their animation and their presence remind me a lot of
Samurai Jack&amp;rsquo;s demon adversary, &lt;em&gt;Aku&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Song of the Sea was nominated for an Oscar in 2015, but lost out to &lt;strong&gt;Frozen&lt;/strong&gt;.
Secret of Kells lost to &lt;strong&gt;Up&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to win an Oscar on a year with a
strong showing by Disney, but neither of these films deserve to be relegate to
second-tier viewing. To those who know these movies, they will become treasured
classics, on the same shelf as Sprited Away or Kiki&amp;rsquo;s Delivery Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As foreign as the films may be to American viewers who only know them from their
Oscar nominations, all the elements you expect in an animated movie are there.
Action, adventure, whimsical sidekicks, villains.  And yet, they never feel like
they are trying to be Disney, like much non-Disney American animation. It more
feels like a nod to the giants of animation than an attempt to win audience by
copying them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secret of Kells and Song of the Sea are both often available on Amazon and
Netflix streaming sites. I highly recommend them to anyone who loves a
good fairy tale on a rainy day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>